At the Ruins of the King's Tomb,
located in the northern lands
To the eighteen of you
who passed the first test...
第一次試験合格者18名
Second Test Proctor
Sense, First-Class Mage
First, congratulations on making it here.
まずは 合格おめでとう
I hear people speculate all kinds of things
about my tests based on past results.
私が担当する試験に関しては
これまでの結果から
実にさまざまな憶測が飛び交っていると聞く
I'm sure there are some of you
who have heard such rumors,
君たちの中にも噂を耳にした者はいるだろう
but you needn't prepare
yourselves for the worst.
だが 身構える必要はない
The test is very simple.
試験は至ってシンプル
Anyone who wishes to become a first-class
mage should be able to pass it with ease.
一級魔法使いを目指す者ならば
難なく切り抜けられるものだ
Now, allow me to explain
the details of the second test.
それでは 第二次試験の詳細を説明する
You're there like the wind
貴方は風のように
Closing your eyes at sunset
目を閉じては夕暮れ
I wonder what's on your mind
何を思っているんだろうか
Beyond Journey's End
With your eyelids open
目蓋を開いていた
貴方の目はビイドロ
Your eyes shone like glass
It faintly smelled like a sunny day
少しだけ晴るの匂いがした
晴れに晴れ 花よ咲け
Clear up the sky, let flowers bloom
Bloom and blame it on the sunny sky
咲いて晴るのせい
Even the rain, when it stops
降り止めば雨でさえ
Will make you shine in the sunlight
貴方を飾る晴る
Calm the stirring sounds in my heart
胸を打つ音よ凪げ
僕ら晴る風
We go like the sunny wind
あの雲も越えてゆけ
Go on and fly over that cloud
遠くまだ遠くまで
Further and further away
Episode 23: Conquering the Labyrinth
For the second test,
you will be raiding a dungeon.
第二次試験は迷宮攻略だ
You will raid the Ruins of the King's Tomb.
君たちには零落の王墓の攻略を行ってもらう
There is only one condition for passing:
you must reach the deepest floor of the tomb.
合格条件はただ一つ
零落の王墓の最深部までたどり着くことだ
I am a pacifist. I dislike fighting.
私は平和主義者でね
争いは好まない
Therefore, everyone who reaches
the bottom will pass.
よって たどり着いた者は全員合格とする
Wait.
待て
Many adventurers have failed to return
from this unexplored dungeon.
ここは多くの冒険者が帰らぬ者になった
未踏破の迷宮だ
Are you planning to fail
all the test-takers again?
また合格者を出さないつもりか
What are you talking about?
何を言っている?
You are attempting to reach
the pinnacle of magehood.
君たちが目指しているのは魔法使いの最高峰だ
First-class mages make
the impossible possible.
不可能を可能にするのが一級魔法使い
You must forge ahead, regardless of whether
or not anyone's been there before you.
未踏破だろうが前人未踏だろうが
ねじ伏せて突き進むんだ
How should we prove we've reached the bottom?
最深部にたどり着いたということをどう証明すればよいのですか?
Should we return with treasure?
金銀財宝でも持ち帰ればいいのかしら
You won't need to prove it.
証明の必要はない
私も共に最深部まで潜る
I will descend to the bottom
of the dungeon with you.
Naturally, I will not be
assisting the test-takers.
無論 受験者に手は貸さんがな
Also, each of you will receive
one of these bottles.
それと
全員にこの瓶を渡しておこう
It's an escape golem developed
by the first-class mage Lernen.
一級魔法使いレルネンが開発した
"脱出用ゴーレムだ"
When the bottle is shattered,
瓶を割ればゴーレムが現れ
the golem will manifest
and carry you out of the dungeon.
迷宮の外まで運び出してくれる
They're still prototypes,
but they're safe enough.
試作段階だが安全性は十分だ
Using your bottle means you fail the test,
使用者は不合格となるが
but I urge you to do so if you become unable
to continue due to injuries or otherwise.
負傷などで
試験継続不可能と判断したら
迷わず使うんだ
I have no intention of allowing mages
with promising futures to die here.
将来有望な人材が死ぬのは許容できん
Also, the bottles will shatter
automatically at dawn tomorrow.
それと明日の夜明けには
自動で瓶が割れるようになっている
That is the time limit of the second test.
それが第二次試験の期限となる
Now, let the test begin.
それでは試験開始だ
There are multiple entrances.
入り口が複数あるな
This seems to be a dungeon
of the Unified Dynasty.
統一王朝期の迷宮のようだな
Dungeons of that era have multiple entrances,
この時代の迷宮は入り口が複数あるが
but they all lead to the deepest level.
どれも最深部に通じている
それぞれの入り口を調べれば
Examining the entrances should allow us
ある程度の内部構造が分かるだろう
to determine the internal
structure of the dungeon.
The group should split up and—
全員で手分けをして…
Why are you acting like
we're working together?
なぜ協力する流れになっているんだ
There's no reason for us to fight this time.
今回の試験には争う要素がない
It's better for all of us to cooperate.
全員で協力した方がいい
I can't agree to that.
それは無理だな
Unlike in the first test, our companions'
survival isn't a condition for passing the test.
第一次試験とは違って
合格条件に仲間の生存がない
We're not obligated to help each other,
徒党を組んだところで
仲間を助ける義理はないし
and we even risk becoming someone's
sacrificial pawn if the need arises.
いざという時は
捨て石にされるリスクまである
You in particular seem
knowledgeable about dungeons.
特にあんたは迷宮に詳しいようだしな
I'm going alone.
俺は1人で行く
We're all carrying baggage from the first test.
第一次試験のしがらみもある
At the very least, I can't work
with anyone I don't know well.
少なくともよく知らねえヤツとは 組めねえよな
Let's go.
行くぞ
Wait for me.
ちょっと 待ってよ
Those fools. Why don't they realize
working together is better?
バカが
協力することの優位性に気付けんとは
Let's go, Fern.
行くよ フェルン
Are you sure, Ms. Frieren?
いいんですか フリーレン様
There's no chance of everyone
working together anymore.
協力はダメだね
もう成立しないよ
I see.
I shall accompany your group.
では私は君たちについていこう
You seem like you'll have the
safest time reaching the bottom.
君たちが一番安全に最深部にたどり着けそうだ
You'd better not interfere.
邪魔しないでよね
I shall neither interfere nor assist you.
しないよ 邪魔も手助けも
This is the safest route.
ここが一番安全なルートだよ
We'll proceed with caution
while mapping the dungeon.
マッピングしながら 慎重に進もうか
The floor there is trapped. Be careful.
そこの床
罠だから気を付けて
You always know so much about dungeons.
相変わらず 迷宮に詳しいですね
I didn't always.
前はそうでもなかったんだけれどもね
It was Himmel who loved dungeons.
ヒンメルが迷宮好きだったから
We entered so many of them
to hunt down monsters.
魔物の討伐依頼で
たくさんの迷宮に潜ったんだよ
What do you mean, he loved dungeons?
迷宮が好きって どういうことですか?
It's exactly what it sounds like.
言葉通りの意味だよ
He said they excited him.
わくわくするんだってさ
It doesn't make sense, does it?
訳が分からないよね
These stairs lead to the next floor.
次の階層に続く階段だな
I see. Then we chose the wrong route.
そうか
こっちのルートはハズレだな
Let's head back to the last branch.
さっきの分かれ道まで戻るぞ
そうですね
Indeed.
Why? We're looking for the monster
at the bottom of the dungeon.
なぜだ?
俺たちの目的は最深部にいる魔物だ
When will you learn, Eisen?
いつになったら学ぶんだ アイゼン
In a dungeon, one must explore the entire
floor before proceeding to the next one.
迷宮は1つの階層を全て踏破してから
次に進むものだ
Every adventurer knows that.
冒険者の常識だぞ
I've never heard that before.
そんな常識はないぞ
You think I'm being foolish, don't you?
バカみたいだって思っているだろう
But isn't it best to be able to have fun
while helping people?
楽しんで人助けができるのなら
それが一番じゃないか
It won't always be like this.
いつまでもこうはいかないよ
旅が進めば
As we travel, the dungeons will
become more life-threatening.
命懸けの迷宮も増えてくる
That's right.
そうだそうだ
I intend to enjoy it until the end.
最後まで楽しむよ
I'll have fun adventuring, raiding dungeons,
楽しく冒険して 迷宮に潜って
defeating monsters, finding treasure,
魔物を倒して 宝を探して
and before I know it,
I'll have saved the world.
気が付いたら世界を救っていたような…
That's the kind of adventure I want to have.
そんな旅がしたいんだ
Besides...
それに
分かれ道の先にあるのは 珍しい魔導書かもしれないしな
There might be a rare grimoire
down the path left untraveled.
What are you doing? Let's hurry back.
何やってるの 早く戻るよ
What?
It really doesn't make sense, does it?
本当に訳が分からないよね
Kanne, let's go.
カンネ 行こうぜ
In the end, only the five of us stayed.
結局 残ったのは5人か
We could've beaten the dungeon easily
全員で協力して役割分担をすれば
if we'd all worked together
and assigned roles.
攻略の可能性は十分にあった
We had enough skilled mages to make it happen.
それだけの実力者がそろっていたはずだったのだがな
Denken, not everyone is as pragmatic as you.
デンケン
みんながあんたほど割り切れるわけじゃない
It's like what you said
toward the end of the first test.
第一次試験の最後に あんたも言っていただろう
It must not have sat right with them.
気に食わなかったんだろうさ
Think of it this way:
only the smartest have remained.
より賢い連中が残った
そう思えばいい
At the very least,
少なくとも この中に
there aren't any idiots here to hold us back
by falling for simple traps like mimics.
ミミックのような単純な罠に掛かって
足を引っ張るバカはいない
Isn't that good enough, Denken?
それでいいだろう デンケン
I doubt anyone that foolish would
be taking this test to begin with.
そんなバカがこの試験にいるものか
Let's go.
行くぞ
This mana...
この魔力…
It might be a grimoire.
魔導書かも
Ms. Frieren, you saw the results
of that Mikheit spell.
フリーレン様
"ミークハイト"の判別結果は見ましたよね
It's a mimic.
ミミックです
Fern, that spell is only 99% accurate.
フェルン その魔法の精度は99％だよ
And what if it is?
それがどうかしたのですか?
Historical discoveries have been made by
great mages who recognized that remaining 1%.
残りの1％を見破った偉大な魔法使いたちがいたからこそ
歴史的な発見があったんだ
It's just as I thought.
やっぱりそうだ
There's a valuable grimoire inside here.
この中身は貴重な魔導書だよ
That's what my experience
as a mage is telling me.
私の魔法使いとしての経験がそう告げている
It's dark and scary in here!
暗いよ! 怖いよ!
It's dark! I'm scared!
暗いっ! 怖いっ!
It's dark and scary!
暗いよ! 怖いよ!
Maybe I chose the wrong people to follow.
ついていく人たち 間違えたかな
Don't step on the floor in the center.
中心の床は踏むなよ
The ceiling will come crashing down on you.
天井が落ちてくるぞ
Is that person-shaped stain there...
まさか そこの人型の染みって…
Brutal. It doesn't even leave bones behind.
えげつないな 骨も残らないのか
Gargoyles!
ガーゴイルだ
Denken, someone got trapped.
デンケン 1人閉じ込められた
I know.
分かっている
壁の向こうだ
She's on the other side of the wall.
Stand back.
下がっていろ
It didn't work.
やはりダメか
Then we have no choice.
やむを得ん
Break your bottle!
瓶を割れ!
Wow.
すげぇ
We're already down another test-taker.
もう 1人脱落か
Letting your guard down for a moment
here could cost you your life.
少しの油断が命取りになるな
So these are the Ruins of the King's Tomb.
これが零落の王墓か
Hey, Fern. Can I make a suggestion?
ねぇフェルン ちょっといいかな
Stop pulling. You're going to rip me in half.
いったん引っ張るのやめよ ちぎれちゃうから
Okay.
はい
To save someone from a mimic,
you should push in instead.
こういう時はね
逆に押し込むんだよ
ミミックがオエってなって噛むのやめるから
It makes the mimic choke and stop biting.
Is it a dog or something?
犬か何かなんですか
I'm safe.
助かった
Honestly.
まったく
How did you get out of those
when you were by yourself?
1人の時はどう処理していたんですか?
攻撃魔法で内側から爆破していた
By blowing them up from the inside
with offensive magic.
But I don't like to do it
since it makes my hair frizz up.
でも 髪の毛がチリチリになっちゃうから
嫌なんだよね
I'm back.
ただいま
I have ringlets now.
縦ロールになっちゃった
So that's why you'd sometimes
have a different hairstyle.
時々髪形変わっていたのって
Why?
何で?
Let's pull ourselves together and keep going.
じゃあ 気を取り直して
攻略を進めるよ
Gargoyles.
ガーゴイルだ
We'll defeat them before they start moving.
動き出す前に倒すよ
We've been seeing these
medals all over the place.
このメダル いろんな場所で見かけますね
どっかの好事家が集めてるらしいよ
Apparently some dilettante collects them.
This looks like the main route.
Let's turn back.
こっちは正規のルートっぽいから引き返すよ
何で?
Why?
We're progressing more
smoothly than I expected.
思ったよりも順調ですね
It does seem a bit odd
for an unexplored dungeon.
確かに 未踏破の迷宮にしてはおかしいね
構造的にもう最深部は近いはずだし
Judging by its construction,
we should be nearing the bottom, too.
Either way, don't let your guard down.
どちらにせよ油断は禁物だね
Let's take a break in the
next burial chamber we find.
次の玄室を見つけたら
いったん休憩にしようか
We've acquired some pretty nice stuff.
結構いい物 手に入ったね
ガラクタにしか見えませんが
It just looks like junk to me.
Huh.
I don't get it.
分からんな
Neither do I.
ですよね
Why do those things make her happy?
あんな物で喜ぶだなんて
She's rubbing it on her cheek.
頬ずりしてる
You're the one I don't understand, Fern.
私が分からないのは君だよ フェルン
I've never seen a mage
as skilled as you at your age.
その若さで
君ほど優秀な魔法使いは見たことがない
You must have trained rather hard.
相当な修練を積んだはずだ
And yet I sense no passion
or determination in you.
なのに君からは情熱も執念も感じない
You're a strange girl.
不思議な子だ
I became a proper mage
to repay a debt to someone.
私はとある人に恩を返すために
一人前の魔法使いになりました
That was my life's goal at the time.
それは当時の私の人生の目標で
ただただ全力で
I devoted all my effort to achieving it
without considering anything
that would come after that.
その先があるだなんて 考えもしませんでした
I must've used up all my passion
and determination then.
きっと その時に
情熱も執念も 使い果たしてしまったのでしょう
Then why do you continue
searching for magic?
ならなぜ君は 魔法の探求を続けているんだ?
Ms. Frieren seems to be
having fun, doesn't she?
フリーレン様 楽しそうでしょう
Yes.
そうだな
The first time I entered a dungeon,
私が初めて迷宮に潜った時も
Ms. Frieren joyfully smiled
while collecting magic junk.
フリーレン様は ガラクタみたいな魔導具を集めて
楽しそうに笑っていました
It made me smile, too.
釣られて笑ってしまったんです
I think I continue searching for magic
because I like seeing her happy.
きっと私は そんなフリーレン様の姿が好きだから
一緒に魔法を追い求めているんだと思います
We should get going.
そろそろ先に進みましょう
Looks like I was right
to follow you after all.
やっぱり君たちについてきて正解だったようだ
I'm sure you can enjoy
even this brutal dungeon.
きっと君たちなら この過酷な迷宮も楽しむことができる
The atmosphere has changed.
雰囲気が変わったな
Maybe we're near the bottom.
最深部が近いのかもな
Wirbel.
ヴィアベル
What? Can't walk any—
何だ もう歩けなく…
I'm restrained.
拘束されたわ
There are three mages concealing their mana.
魔力を消した魔法使いが3人
It's an ambush.
奇襲よ
Oh?
Scharf, block their vision.
シャルフ 視界を遮れ
The spell cast on Ehre is Sorganeil.
エーレにかけられた魔法は
"ソルガニール"だ
I know.
分かっている
No wonder the Ruins of the King's Tomb
have never been conquered.
零落の王墓が難攻不落だったわけだぜ
I wasn't expecting to encounter these here.
まさか こんなものがいるだなんてね
Scharf, you're on me.
シャルフは"俺"を
Ehre, you're on Scharf.
エーレは"シャルフ"を狙え
And I'll take on Ehre.
俺は"エーレ"をたたく
Let's do this.
突破するぞ
It's a replica made using magic.
魔法によって作られた複製体だな
It must be the work of demons or monsters.
魔族か魔物の仕業だろう
But I've never seen such a perfect copy
of another person before.
だが これほど完壁な他者の複製は見たことがない
Its mana and skills were
the same as yours, Laufen.
魔力も技量もラオフェンと同等だった
So was its behavior.
所作もそうだ
It's possible even our memories were used.
記憶さえも利用している可能性がある
I don't like this.
あまりいい気分じゃないね
The one saving grace is that it's
instantly recognizable as a fake.
救いがあるとすれば
一目見て偽物だと分かるところだな
At the very least, there's no danger
of us attacking each other.
少なくとも 同士討ちの危険性はない
If whoever cast this spell can control
multiple copies simultaneously,
仮にこの魔法の使い手が
複数の複製体を同時に操れるとしたら
they must be terrifyingly powerful.
恐ろしいほどの脅威になりますね
Either way, we were right to team up.
どちらにせよ徒党を組んでいて正解だったな
It gives us more options
for dealing with them.
対処できる手段も増える
Denken, can we deal with that, too?
デンケン あれも対処できるのか
The one thing I can say
is that if this weren't a test,
一つだけ言えるのは…
これが試験でなかったら儂はとうに瓶を割っておる
I would've shattered my bottle
a long time ago.
And I'm alright (I'll be alright)
And I'm alright
Yeah I hear you
Yeah, I hear you (I care about you)
伸びた髪を風がからかってる
The wind teases this hair that's longer now
There's meaning in everything
全部意味があるよ
Even the days that came to a halt
立ち止まった日々も
Now that I finally understand,
I've caught up to you
今さらわかってあなたに追いついたよ
See, things that couldn't have been
ほら この目じゃなければ
見えなかったものが
Seen if it weren't for these eyes
どうして 溢れてく
Why? They begin to overflow
I won't ask to see you, so at least
せめて 会いたいよなんて言わないから
Let me remember the past, just for today
ねえ 今日だけは思い出していいかな
だからあなたとまた巡りあったら
So, if we were to meet again
No more hesitations, I'd choose the present
もう迷わない今を選ぶんだろう
Anytime, anywhere, yah (wherever you are)
Anytime anywhere yah
Anytime, anywhere (smile for me)
Anytime anywhere
I'll be there (close your eyes,
and I'll always be there)
I'll be there
Even if there are no absolutes
絶対なんてなくても
I'm always aware of your thoughts
いつでも届いているから
Those tears will be alright,
dawn will surely break
その涙だって大丈夫
きっと夜が明けるよ
I'm whispering our lullaby
for you to come back home
Now then, what are we going to do about this?
Smells nice.
It's time.
If we're evenly matched,
That's not funny.
then who wins will come down to luck.
Could you please look into my eyes?
So it's not impossible.
How much time do you need?
Episode 24
Perfect Replicas
They're perfect replicas.
完璧な複製体だ